Walt Kuhn Family Papers and Armory Show
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Armory Show Records, 1912-1963, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-2, 27-31, OV 36; 3.6 linear feet)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1914, 1.1:
    - Artists and Lenders Correspondence, 1912-1913, 1.1.2:
      - Europe, General, P-Y, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Stein, M.
        Vollard, Ambroise
        Waldau, Grete
        Yeats, Jack B.
    - Insurers, Packers, and Shippers Correspondence, 1912-1913, 1.1.3:
      Correspondence with Insurers, Packers, and Shippers contains inventories, receipts, and correspondence detailing arrangements for the physical handling and security of works included in the show, and correspondence relating to insurance claims on exhibited works.
      Artists' and lenders' correspondence regarding insurance and shipping is filed in Artists and Lenders Correspondence (Series 1.1.2). Extensive correspondence regarding the shipment of works to Chicago and Boston is filed in Traveling Exhibition Correspondence (Series 1.1.5). Additional shipping information can be found in the annotated catalogs filed in Printed Material and Memorabilia (Series 1.5).
      - Adams Express Company, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Austin, Baldwin and Co. (Mr. Fleming), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Blaiklock Bros. Limited, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Chenue, J., 1912, (Oversized material housed in Box 27) (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Compagnie Générale Transatlantique, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Doll and Richards, Inc., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Hensel, Bruckmann and Lorbacher, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Lloyd Anglo-Francais, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - O'Brien Art Galleries (see Adams Express Company) (Box 1)
      - Pottier, Ch., 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Frederic B. Thomason, Insurer, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - United States Lloyd's, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Wetsch (Gebrüder Wetsch, Wetsch's Kunst und Mobiltransport in München), 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - General C-W, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 41)
        Collector of Customs, New York City
        H. Desmidt and Co.
        Harlem Terminal Storage and Warehouse Company
        Milch, Mr. D.
        Quinn, John (see Watson, John)
        Watson, John
        Willard, Mr. (New York; see Compagnie Générale Transatlantique)
        Wilson, Louis
      - Packing list of J. Chenue, 1912, (Oversized material scanned with Box 1, F32) (Box 27)
    - Publicity, 1912-1913, 1.1.4:
      The bulk of correspondence concerning the production and promotion of the Armory Show is filed here. Subjects include real estate matters, press coverage, art work reproductions, invitations, publications, merchandise, and fundraising. Correspondence by artists, dealers, and collectors concerning these subjects has been filed in Artists and Lenders Correspondence (Series 1.1.2).
      - Beatty, John W. (Carnegie Institute), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - General A-B and illegible, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 43)
        [3 letters with illegible signatures]
        Abbott, J.B. (Art Association of Montreal)
        Abendschein, Albert
        A.C. Rowe and Son
        Allen, C.L.
        Alverson Press
        Angue, D.G. (Everybody's Magazine)
        Ashwell, Thomas E. (Arts and Decoration)
        Austin, W.C. (Actors' Fund of America)
        Bach, Richard J. (Columbia University, School of Architecture)
        Bain, George Grantham (Daily Illustrated News Service)
        Bains, William M.
        Barnard College
        Bell, E. (The Outlook)
        Berg, G.L. (Washington State Art Association)
        Bidwell, C.B. (Atlanta Art Association)
        Bied, Louis (see Druet, E.)
        Blake, W.B. (The Independent, New York)
        Brinton, Christian (The Players, New York)
        Bowerman, George F. (Public Library of the District of Columbia)
        Budworth, W.S.
        Burlington Magazine
        Burrell, Mr. (Department of Agriculture, Canada)
      - Churchill, Alfred Vance (Smith College Art Dept.), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Conley, Col. Louis D. (69th Regiment Infantry N.G.N.Y.), 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Conley, Col. Louis D. (69th Regiment Infantry N.G.N.Y.) (copies), 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Crowninshield, Frank (The Century Co.), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - General C-E, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        Carruth, Hayden (Woman's Home Companion)
        Chase, Otto B.
        Clark, G.G. (Blackman-Ross Company, Advertising)
        Cobb, Anna L. (Department of Applied Art, Board of Education, Cleveland, OH)
        Cohen, Lewis
        Colgate and Company
        College of the City of New York
        Columbia University Faculty of Fine Arts
        Consolidated Gas Co.
        Croker National Fire Prevention and Engineering Co.
        Crowley, Mrs. F.B. (Art Advisory Committee, Des Moines, IA)
        Curtiss, J.P. (Marconi Wireless Daily Papers)
        Davidge, Clara
        Dion, F. L. (E.E. Vreeland, Advertising, Inc.)
        Douglas, Mr. (F.W. Woolworth)
        Druet, E. (Photographie D'Oeuvres D'Art)
        du Bois, Guy Pène (see Ashwell, Thomas E.)
      - Holland, R.A. (City Art Museum, Saint Louis, MO), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Irving, F. (Geo. R. Read and Co., Real Estate), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - General F-I, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        Fackenthal, F.D. (Columbia University)
        Falcke, Dr. (see Wenzel, R.A.)
        Fant, John
        Flagg, Maurice I. (Minnesota State Art Society)
        Fox, William Henry (Central Museum, Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences; see also Hooper, Franklin W.)
        Gardner, Isabella S.
        Gaylor, A.C.(Arts and Decoration)
        Goewey, Ed (Kansas City Post)
        Goodale and Hanson
        Hamilton, Mr. (Holmes Electric Protective Company)
        Hefter, Hannah Henrietta
        Henderson, Helen W. (The Philadelphia Inquirer)
        Hermann, Mr. (Verlag Der Sturm)
        Herzfeld-Phillipson Co., Boston Store
        Holm, Frits V. (The Copenhagen)
        Hooper, Franklin W. (Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences)
        Howells, John Mead
      - Koehler, Robert (Minneapolis Society of Fine Arts and School of Art), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Lamb, James E., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Loweree, W.D. (The Whitehead and Hoag Co.), 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - General J-L, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        Johnson, John G.
        Juley, Peter A.
        Katz, Miss (Greenhut-Siegel Cooper Co.)
        Keipp, Mary M.
        Keyser, P. de (Merick Reynolds Fine Arts)
        Kneeland, Marjorie (Music School Settlement)
        Knoedler, Roland
        Komroff, Manuel (Francisco Ferrer Association)
        Krone, W.
        Laker, John W.E.
        Laurvik, J. Neilson
        Lenygon, H. (Lynygon and Morant, Inc.)
        Levy, Florence N. (American Art Annual; see also Bowerman, George F.)
        Lublin, Mrs. C. Owen (Town and Country)
      - General M-N, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        Mahlberg, Paul
        Major, Lilian D.
        Morison, David
        Mosley, Helen E.
        Myers, John Andrew (Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts)
        Nelson, W.H. (The International Studio)
        New York Armory (see Conley, Col. Louis D.)
        New York Edison Co.
        New York Public Library
        New York Telephone Co.
        New York University
        Noël, Rev. Brother (La Salle Academy)
      - General O-R, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        Oppenheimer, Mr.
        Pardle, William S.
        Pardo, L. Lara (Cosmos magazine)
        Postmaster, Madison Square Garden
        Poth, Mr. (the Sportsmens Show)
        President, The White House
        Preyer, D.C.
        Putnam, Alice
        Reid, Miss C.W. (Normal College of the City of NY)
        Robbins, Leona
        Roberts, Mary F.
        Roeder, Miss (R.H. Macy and Co.)
        Romeike, Henry (Henry Romeike Inc.)
        Roosevelt, Theodore
        Rutter, Frank
      - Sulzer, William (Governor of New York State), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - General S-T, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 59)
        Sage, Cornelia (Buffalo Fine Arts Academy)
        San Francisco Chronicle
        Saturday Evening Post
        Schulman, Gabriel
        Schultheis, Henry (Henry Schultheis Co.)
        Sloan, Anna M. (The Masses Publishing Co.)
        Staats Zeitung
        Stevens, George W. (Toledo Museum of Art)
        Teachers College
        Thomson, John (The Free Library of Philadelphia)
        Titus, A.B. (International Panama-California Exposition)
      - General, W-Z, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 60)
        Wager-Smith, Miss Curtis
        Watt, D.A.
        Wenzel, R.A. (Imperial German Consulate, New York)
        Wiegand, Henry H. (Charcoal Club)
        Willard, Elisa May (Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh)
        Willis, Mr. (Office of the Fire Commissioner, New York)
        Ziegler, Francis S. (The Philadelphia Record)
    - Traveling Exhibition, 1912-1914, 1.1.5:
      This series documents the modified exhibitions sent to the Art Institute of Chicago (March 24 to April 16, 1913) and the Copley Society of Boston (April 28 to May 19, 1913). The bulk of correspondence is between Armory Show organizers and officials at the Chicago and Boston venues, including Walt Kuhn, Arthur B. Davies, Walter Pach, Frederick James Gregg, Elmer MacRae, and John Quinn, William M.R. French, Arthur T. Aldis, N.H. Carpenter, J.F. Coolidge, Holker Abbott, and Desmond Fitzgerald.
      Correspondence among exhibit organizers regarding sales made during the traveling exhibition is also filed here. A contract between the AAPS and the Copley Society, referred to in a telegram of March 4, 1913, is filed with that telegram. Correspondence regarding a contract dispute between the AAPS and the Copley Society is also filed in this series. Arrangement is chronological.
      Additional correspondence relating to the traveling exhibition can be found in Walt Kuhn's letters to Vera Kuhn in Organizers' Letters (Series 1.1.1).
      - Traveling Exhibition, 1912-1914, (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 61-66)
    - Sales Correspondence, 1913, 1.1.6:
      Sales Correspondence contains the bulk of correspondence regarding the sale, payment, and delivery of works bought at the exhibition, as well as inquiries and acknowledgements made by the buyers and artists. This correspondence is most often of a perfunctory nature, listing works and prices or other arrangements.
      In addition to correspondence in this series, information about exhibition sales can be found in Traveling Exhibition Correspondence (Series 1.1.5), Armory Show Notes (Series 1.4) and in the marked catalogs in Printed Materials and Memorabilia (Series 1.5).
      - Artz and de Bois, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - Druet, Emile (E. Druet Galerie), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      - Goltz, Hans (Neue Kunst), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - General, A-K, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 70)
        Barnes, A.C.
        Blanchet, Alexander
        Boudelle, E.A.
        Bourgeois, Stephan (see Chapman, Frederic A.)
        Burroughs, Bryson (Metropolitan Museum of Art)
        Chabaud, August
        Chapman, Frederic A. (see also Torrey, Frederic C.)
        Clark, Stephen C.
        Coluzzi, Howard
        Dearden, Frank Jay
        DeKay, Charles
        Flechtheim, Arthur
        Gliezes, Albert
        Harsted, R.H.
        Hays, Lydia D.
        Henri, Robert
        Hessel, Joseph
        Higgins, Eugene
        Hopper, Edward
        Jansen, F.M.
        Kahnweiller, Henry
        Kretz, Mr.
        Kapferer, Marcel
      - General, L-P, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 71)
        Lee, Arthur
        Lie, Jonas
        Luks, George
        Marcus, George
        McKinney, Ethelyn
        Morris, Dave H.
        Oppenheimer, Louis de L.
        Pach, Walter
        Pascin, Jules
        Picabia, Francis
        Porter, George F.
        Porter, Harold E.
      - Tuttle, William F. (Friends of American Art, Art Institute of Chicago), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      - General, Q-Z, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 73)
        Radeke, E.G.
        Robinson, Boardman
        Russell, Morgan
        Sheldrick, Richard
        Sousa Cardoza, Amadeo De
        Thannhauser, Heinrich
        Uhde, Wilhelm
        Zak, Eugene
  - Domestic Art Committee Records, 1913, 1.2:
    This series contains a record book of works from the United States submitted for inclusion in the Armory Show, showing which works were selected and which rejected. Also found are mailing lists of artists.
    - Mailing lists, circa 1913 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Record Book, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Record Book (copies), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - European Entry Cards, 1912, 1.3:
    This series consists of forms filled out and submitted by artists and dealers for individual works sent to the Armory Show. Forms include the name of the work, the name of the artist, the date of execution, the price of the work for insurance and for sale, the location of the work and the address to which the work was to be returned.
    Forms in German are separated from forms in French, and arrangement is alphabetical by artist.
    - French, circa 1912, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 77-79)
    - French (copies), circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - German, circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Notes, 1912-1913, 1.4:
    This series consists of handwritten and typewritten information related to the Armory Show, including notes in Walter Pach's hand from a conversation with Odilon Redon from December of 1912, a list of artists suggested for inclusion in the show by Picasso and often referred to as "Picasso's list," statistics for attendance and sales, prices of works in an annotated catalog, and a list of purchasers and their mailing addresses. Additional catalogs from the exhibition, both annotated and un-annotated, can be found in Printed Material (Series 1.5). Additional statistics for attendance can be found in Scrapbooks (Series 1.8, Press II, p. 69).
    - Walter Pach's notes from a conversation with Odilon Redon, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Picasso's List, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Picasso's List (copies), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Prices and Purchasers, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Prices and Purchasers (copies), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Statistics and Other Notes, circa 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Printed Material and Memorabilia, 1912-1913, 1.5:
    Printed material in this series includes a blueprint of the Armory installation floor plan; the 1912 catalog of the Sonderbund Internationale Kunst-Austellung in Cologne, Germany, which was sent to Walt Kuhn by Arthur B. Davies and annotated by both men; exhibition catalogs for the New York, Chicago, and Boston exhibitions; printed exhibition announcements and notices; postcards printed with reproductions of art works; pamphlets published by the organizers of the show; two items of memorabilia including an Armory Show button and a lapel pin; and newspaper clippings.
    Several of the catalogs contain annotations. Annotated New York catalogs are marked with prices and other notes; annotated Boston and Chicago catalogs are marked with shipping and packing information. Researchers should note for each of the catalogs, the annotated copies have been digitized. Digitization was not repeated for clean duplicates of catalogs.
    An additional annotated catalog can be found in Notes (Series 1.4) under the heading "Prices and Purchasers." Additional clippings can be found in Scrapbooks (Series 1.8). Transcripts of Walt Kuhn's translation of Gauguin's "Noa-Noa" are filed under Writings of Walt Kuhn (Series 1.6).
    - Blueprint of Armory Show Floorplan, circa 1913, (Oversized material housed in OV 36) (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Button and Lapel Pin, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Button and Lapel Pin (copies), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Clippings, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Exhibition announcements and notices, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Exhibition announcements and notices (copies), 1913 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Exhibition catalogs for the Armory Show (Box 2)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art, New York, N.Y., 1913 February 17 to March 15, (See also folder 7) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art; Supplement containing additions, errata, and exhibits cataloged but not received, New York, N.Y., 1913 February 17 to March 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art; Supplement containing additions, errata, and exhibits cataloged but not received, New York, N.Y. (copies), 1913 February 17 to March 15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art, Chicago, Ill., 1913 March 24 to April 16, (See also folder 8) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art, Boston, Mass. ,1913 April 28 to May 19, (See also folder 8) (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art (annotated), New York, N.Y., 1913 February 17 to March 15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - International Exhibition of Modern Art (annotated), Boston, Mass. and Chicago, Ill., 1913 March 24 to April 16, and April 28 to May 19 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Internationale Kunst-Ausstellung des Sonderbundes Illustr. Katalog, Cologne, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Internationale Kunst-Ausstellung des Sonderbundes Illustr. Katalog, Cologne (copies), 1912 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pamphlets, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      "Cézanne," by Elie Faure
      "For and Against," edited by Frederick James Gregg
      "Noa-Noa," excepts, by Paul Gauguin, translated by Walt Kuhn
      "Odilon Redon," by Walter Pach
      "A Sculptor's Architecture," by Walter Pach
    - Pamphlets (copies), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Postcard reproductions of works exhibited, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Postcard reproductions of works exhibited (copies), 1913, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Oversized Blueprint of Armory Show Floorplan, (Oversized material scanned with Box 1, F88) (Box OV 36)
  - Writings of Walt Kuhn, 1912-1913, 1.6:
    This series contains translations written by Walt Kuhn during his voyage home from Europe in November, 1912. Works include excerpts from Paul Gauguin's "Noa-Noa," which was later published in pamphlet form for sale at the Armory Show, and excerpts from "Letters of a Post Impressionist" by Vincent van Gogh, which was not published. Also included are copyright clearances for both works obtained from the Library of Congress Copyright Office.
    Manuscripts and typescripts are filed together in this subseries. The published pamphlet of the Gauguin translation can be found in Printed Material and Memorabilia (Series 1.5). Additional writings by Walt Kuhn can be found in the Walt Kuhn Family Papers (Series 4).
    - "Noa Noa," Excerpts, by Paul Gauguin, translated by Walt Kuhn, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Letters of a Post Impressionist," by Vincent Van Gogh, Translated by Walt Kuhn, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Library of Congress Copyright Office, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, 1912-1913, 1.7:
    This series consists of photographs related to the Armory Show, including installation views, art works, the Duchamp-Villon brothers, and the celebratory beefsteak dinner held on March 8, 1913, taken by Percy Rainford. Photographs include individual prints and one photo album. The photo album consists of platinum prints of works of art that were made into postcards, and an original photograph of the Duchamp-Villon brothers.
    A handful of loose platinum prints of art works and of the Duchamp-Villon brothers match the prints in the photo album in image, tone, and print quality, and have been treated as originals. Copy photographs of images whose originals are not in this collection are filed in Series 1.9: Retrospective Materials. Additional photographs are found in Series 3 and 4.
    - Installation views and Armory building, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Installation views and Armory building (copies), 1913, (3 folders, partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    - Artworks, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Beefsteak Dinner Photograph, 1913, (Oversized materials housed in Box 27) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Beefsteak Dinner Photograph (copies), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Duchamp-Villon brothers, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Duchamp-Villon brothers (copies), 1912 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Photograph Album, 1913, (Oversized material housed in Box 28) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Photograph Album (copies), 1913, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Oversized Beefsteak Dinner Photograph, (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F24) (Box 27)
    - Oversized Photograph Album, (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F28) (Box 28)
  - Scrapbooks, 1912-1913, 1.8:
    This subseries includes two scrapbooks (currently housed in three conservation phase boxes) that document the Armory Show. They include magazine and newspaper clippings; printed materials related to the exhibition; typescript documents of the AAPS related to statistics, public speeches, and circulars; and telegrams remarking on the exhibition. Subjects of the clippings include advance press of the show, diverse responses to the show, satirical cartoons, John Quinn's fight to eliminate the tariff on art, Guzton Borglum's public resignation from the AAPS, and the vice investigation of the show by Chicago authorities.
    Because of the poor quality paper used in the scrapbooks, items in this series have required conservation treatment, which has slightly modified their composition. The Beefsteak dinner menu, which is from the celebratory dinner hosted by the AAPS on March 8, 1913 and is signed by the attendees, was originally included in these scrapbooks, but was later conserved as a separate item. The menu is included in this series with reference to its original page number in the scrapbook. The original binding of volume 2 of the scrapbooks was removed when the volume was conserved, and is housed separately. Another item that was separated from the scrapbooks, a clean copy of the New York edition of the exhibition catalog, is now housed with the other catalogs in Printed Materials and Memorabilia (Series 1.5). Microfilm copies of the scrapbooks as they appeared at the time of accession are available on reels D242-D243.
    In general, scrapbook items are loosely chronological. Duplicates of many of the pamphlets, notices, posters, catalogs and postcards in the scrapbooks are found in Printed Material and Memorabilia (Series 1.5).
    Additional scrapbooks, which are unrelated to the Armory Show, are found in Series 3 and 4.
    - Press I, 1912-1913, (Oversized material housed with Box 29) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Press I (copies), 1912-1913, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    - Press II, part 1, 1913, (Oversized material housed with Box 30) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Press II, part 1 (copies), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Press II, part 2, 1913, (Oversized material housed with Box 31) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Press II, part 2 (copies), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Original Binding for Press II, 1913, (Oversized material housed with Box 27) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Beefsteak Dinner Menu (from Press II, p. 175), 1913, (Oversized material housed with Box 27) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Beefsteak Dinner Menu (from Press II, p. 175) (copies), 1913 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Press I (Oversized Scrapbook), (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F31) (Box 29)
    - Press II, part 1 (Oversized Scrapbook), (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F34) (Box 30)
    - Press II, part 2 (Oversized Scrapbook), (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F36) (Box 31)
    - Oversized Original Binding for Press II, (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F38) (Box 27)
    - Oversized Beefsteak Dinner Menu, (Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F39) (Box 27)
  - Retrospective Materials, 1939-1963, 1.9: